

ARMANDO FLORES

Fullstack Developer

ABOUT ME

My persona Armando Flores is a professional Fullstack Automation Software Developer and QA Project Manager fully capable of assuming the roles thanks to my over 175 IT certificates and over 5 years of experience in the Media and Software Industry, primarily in backend development, services, and microservices but also in Frontend proficient with HTML, CSS and Javascript. He has led the backend and cloud testing teams, focusing on development, automation, performance testing, and cloud platform services and managed self-developed IT ventures, focusing on implementing Software Automation processes to drive business growth in diverse projects. With both hard- (Python, JS, PHP, Java, C/++, Git, Linux, Docker, etc.) and soft skills (Communication skills, Empathy, good listening, and Teamoriented). Passionately solution-oriented.

LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- Germa Fluent
- Spain Native
- French Intermediate
- Catalan Intermediate

SOFT SKILLS

- Highly reslient. Proactive. Communicative
- Empathetic. Critical Thinking.
- Organised towards goals. Easy to manage teams. Effective and Highly people solution oriented.
- Emotionally Intelligent. Excellent Time
 Manager. Resourceful.
- Highly respectful and respected

+4917688067496

https://platzi.com/p/armando -andres-flores/
Berlin, Germany

Armando_zax@hotmail.com

EXPERIENCE

O Freelance Fullstack Developer

2017 - 2024

Independent. Remote

- As a freelancer, gained extensive experience building and deploying fullstack 10+ web projects designing frontend presentation with JS and backend architecture besides managing databases with PHP.
- Developed 2+ websites, taking on roles as creator, designer, developer, and system administrator with PHP and Javascript.
- Developed 3+ Website Games, working both logic and design with Javascript and Python.
- Administered Linux servers, installing WordPress, and creating custom PHP plugins

OSoftware Tester & Automation FullstackDeveloper 2022 - 2023

Innovation Lab. Berlin, Germany

- Participated in an internal project for an Innovation Lab, creating a marketplace website for task-professional matching
- Was involved in the backend and frontend architecture using PHP, JavaScript, React, and Symfony completing project on time.
- Designing and implementing CI/CD automation tests with Jest and Playwright.

Automation Developer & QA Project Manager 2019- 2022

Endava, Berlin, Germany

- Led and motivated the backend team development to finish projects through CI/CD pipelines to support a media platform. Implemented GCP, ElasticSearch from AWS and Grafana for microservices.
- Communicated and discussed with the team the advances and further steps in the projects in 5+ meetings per week.
- Developed 1000+ backend tests using JavaScript, Script and automating CI/CD pipelines in Gitlah

Fullstack Developer & Product Owner 2019- Present

Auragora and Finance, Berlin Germany

- Built the entire website interface from the design, develop, and maintain a featurerich and user-friendly portal administrating databases architecutre and fronted presentation and integration with CMS.
- Responsible for crafting and leading the project's strategic vision with a focus on sustainable profitability achieving audience growth of 100.000+ views with over 2000 subscribers.
- Analyzed market trends and strategic KPI's to drive decision-making processes and implement best practices.

HARD SKILLS

• Agile. AJAX. React. HTML, CSS, Jquery. Javascript. PHP. Python. Java. Next.JS. Express. Algorithms. Automation Testing. CI/CD Chrome. Firefox. Cloud Migration. Cloud Services. Google Cloud Platform. Elastic Search. AWS. Microsoft Azure. Continuous Integration. Containers. Cloud Services. Deployment Pipelines. Docker. Encryption. Git. Github. Gitlab. Grafana. Jest. Jira. Kanban. Kubernetes. Linux. Microservices. Mocha. Mongodb. MS SQL. Mysql. PostgresSQL. MariaDB. Numpy. Pandas. Pytest. Flask. Django. OpenAl. Performance Analysis. Performance Monitoring. Performance Testing. Wordpress. Scrum.

Software Automation Developer

2022- 2023

University Project. Berlin Germany

- Developed 100+ Python development tasks for microgrid model simulator automation project.
- Wrote 50+ unittests using pytest
- Teached 2+ team members soft and hard skills regarding development, administration of CI/CD pipelines in the tech side, and Agile Scrum and Kanban methodologies in the soft skills side.

5G/6G Backhaul Communication Developer 2022-2022 Fraunhofer FOKUS. Berlin Germany

- Developed a sockets library in Python to monitor and report communication parameters, implementing encryption and multipath delivery for optimized performance.
- Implemented Kanban and Scrum agile methodology teaching +1 member agile methodologies and hard skills for completing 30+ tasks on project development
- Designed and implemented load balancing algorithms for efficient data transfer
- Used Python for automation testing and performance monitoring in the research project

EDUCATION & FORMATION -

Bachelor's degree in electronic engineering with specialization in
Information Technology
Technische Universität Berlin

Over 175 Certificates of Soft- & Hardskills courses about IT PLATZI

https://platzi.com/p/armando-andres-flores/